Wyatt here, and on today's segment of Stablecoins and DeFi, I was joined by Dave Taylor, founder
of EtherViews. EtherViews issues non-US stablecoins and stable bonds for currencies and treasuries
with a focus on Mexico, other Latam markets, and beyond. I hope you enjoy this episode and
here is my conversation with Dave. Matt Walsh and Nick Carter are partners
at Castle Island Ventures. All views expressed by them or the guests on this podcast are solely
their opinions and do not reflect the opinions of Castle Island Ventures. Guests and hosts
may maintain positions in the assets discussed on this podcast. You should not treat any opinion
expressed by anyone on this podcast as a specific inducement to make a particular investment or
follow a particular strategy, but only as an expression of their personal opinion. This
podcast is for informational purposes only. Brought down by bad mortgage investments,
Lehman, which has 25,000 employees, will be liquidated. The federal government loans
American International Group, AIG, $85 billion. This is a different kind of market and the Fed
is asleep. The federal government is stepping in to stabilize Fannie Mae and Freddie Mac,
the two mortgage giants that have been threatened by the housing crisis.
The Bank of England has pumped 75 billion pounds more into Britain's ailing economy
with a new round of quantitative easing. You print a couple trillion dollars and all
of a sudden people start to worry. So out of this worry, we have something called the Bitcoin.
Bitcoin. Dave, founder of EtherFuse, thank you for joining us on the podcast. Very excited to chat
today. I think you guys are doing some very interesting things. Would love to kick off
with a personal introduction from yourself if you don't mind so that we can get to know you
even better. Yeah. Thanks for having me. I really appreciate it. Happy to be here. I do listen to
the podcast quite a bit. And so it's going to be nice to drive my son to school in the mornings
and I listen to it and he's going to hear my voice in the next one. So it's going to be cool.
Awesome. My background is computer science. So I've worked in security,
like software engineering security for quite some time. I started out just in like companies.
We call them startups now, but when I was graduating in Arizona, you just call them companies.
I ended up working at Boeing for quite some time. I did PKI management and a lot of the API design
for securely signing software there. Then I went to Apple. I did a lot of network security
and a lot of design between how to normalize or standardize how secure software is used at Apple.
Felt an awesome need to continue to punish myself and grow. And so I decided to go to business school
at that point. Having had like 10 years as a computer scientist and I went to business
school and I met a good friend of mine. He started this company called SendGrid,
which you probably heard of. They were bought by Twilio when we were in business school together.
He IPO'd and said, hey, I want to start a startup studio. The important part is it kind of got some
startup chops or at least some familiarity with how hard it is and how it works. We launched a few
companies together. It was a great experience. And one of the companies we launched together
is Neural Payments. Neural Payments is a huge, huge in scope payments company in the US.
Competitors like Zelle, I think they're raising their Series B right now. So
they've done pretty well in a competitive market. But what was interesting with that is we brought
on a CTO at the time, who is now my co-founder, AJ, who's also my brother, by the way. And together
we built the mechanism to send money outside of Visa's Rails from one account to the next.
It was just this crazy feat of how difficult it was, how antiquated it was, how hard it was.
And it really became astonishing to us how what we see is not what happens. In our purview,
or I would say the periphery of what we're focused on, you start to hear the blockchain getting
quicker and faster. And it just became obvious to us that this was the future. Even though I was
pretty comfortable, we were working on some cool stuff. We said, hey, I think the blockchain is the
future. So let's get into it. Up until this point of EtherFuse, that was my history as an engineer
who jumped into business and started some startups and then went head first into probably, I would
say, one of the more complex things I've ever done in my life. And to be clear, you discovered crypto
after you became a businessman in business school. That wasn't during the engineering period.
I was always on the sidelines. I always said, oh, I should have bought Bitcoin. I was more into being
a software engineer and into cryptography, the old school one. After really feeling the pain of
payments, it was really when I started to think about it and go, holy crap, this is the future.
And a bit to the point of EtherFuse, were you a Bitcoiner early on or were you interested in,
it sounds like you highlighted the cryptography piece and maybe what you could do with assets
more broadly. I really only focused on PKI. So I wasn't a Bitcoiner back then. In fact,
I thought about it, I think in 2013, my neighbor worked for Google, this story kills me.
And I went and I bought like a little Arduino or something because everyone was mining on nothing
back then. I was like, oh, I'm going to go figure out how to mine. And he stopped me. He's like,
you're too late. It's already done. And so I just kind of gave up on the idea and I kind of hate
him now. That was not correct. But I think it was like 2013 or 2012. So I could have avoided all
this stress and just gone straight to owning Bitcoin. Yeah. Probably the person who's had
the most adverse monetary effect on your life. Exactly. And he doesn't even know it. I haven't
even told him so. Speak a little bit more to EtherFuse if you don't mind. You guys are,
I'd say broadly in the stablecoin space as opposed to the Bitcoin and other assets space.
I can take off from where I left off with my personal story into how we started EtherFuse.
And then that can kind of lead into our mission. But we three years ago said, okay, everyone at
the time was proposing that nothing on chain was a security. Like they would probably,
this isn't a security. And we just hypothesized, well, what would the workload look like if we
said it was a security? It did some research in the US on how we could do it. And it just became
overwhelmingly obvious like we're going to get nowhere in the US. And so our goal was, okay,
let's tokenize the security. Say it's a security. How do we do that?
And so we did a bunch of research on the world and said, where do the incentives lie? Meaning,
what's the biggest nation where the economy and the demographics of that nation are such that if
we could bring in the tokenization of assets on chain, that the government would benefit quite
a bit from it and the nation would benefit from it. And if we can find that, then we'll go there
because we think if we engage with regulators there, that they'll be incentivized to say yes.
So back then it was like, we looked at remittance flows, cost of credit, financial access,
what percentage of the population has access to finances and the ability to move money.
And so back then there were three big ones. It was India, China, and Mexico.
Just kind of thought for one second, would China let us come in and build a security on chain and
influence their monetary system and felt, no, that's not going to happen.
I've actually done a lot of work with India at Apple and India is a great country, of course,
but it's also pretty defensive to foreign products. And so we felt, okay, we're going to hit a road
block here. Looked deeper and deeper in Mexico and just felt like, hey, we think we could make an
impact here. So three years ago, we went to Mexico and we started to interface with, it's a funny
story. We literally just went there and we're like, okay, where's the lawyer? Where's the bank?
And learned how we could interface with the SEC of Mexico. It's called the CNBV.
Inquired if there's a process for new technology. And we found out there was a process. It's called
the sandbox model. They have similar ones around the world. I think it's based off the one in
England, but you could engage the CNBV and you could say, hey, we have this new technology.
It's a net good for the country and we propose doing it. And we think this is a security and we
think that you should regulate it and tell us how. We worked with them for two years and the irony is
they came back and told us, we don't think this is a security after the first year.
And so then we went back and said, actually, we're pretty sure it's a security,
which this is counter to what's happening in the world. Everyone else is like proposing nothing's
a security. So we re-engage with them three times. And the third time we asked them to write
publicly all the reasons why our protocol does not constitute a security. So the final thing
we got from them is a no action letter stating why things designed as they are through our
protocol do not constitute a security. When was that? What year did you get the
no action letter? It was like a year and a half ago.
No action letter a year and a half ago. That was valuable.
What we did is if you go to our app, it gives us a huge competitive advantage in Mexico.
And so what we did is we kind of like, like the FBI does, we blacked out
anything that gives a huge competitive advantage. And then we had a judge notarize it,
making the statements that say, I agree that this document says either views can do what
they can do. We've used that to essentially establish the relationships with big banks
like BBVA and Activer and Santander and all around the world to integrate with the banking
system there. So it's been hugely valuable for us. I think even if you sold our company for parts,
it's worth quite a bit. We're the only company in Mexico with any sort of guidance on how to
tokenize assets. And Mexico is quite a big economy. So that's how we got started. That's
the genesis of either views is go out, do some work and get guidance on how to tokenize assets.
I love that you guys took the approach of what if everything is a security
and where can we go to produce the most value at a time when most people are taking the attitude of
what is the biggest market and let's somehow not be a security?
Yeah, we looked at it as I felt the blockchain was like the internet. So it's like, okay,
I make a website from the US, but people from Europe can go there. And so if I can comfortably
be regulated somewhere and I can connect to the blockchain, I have a connection to this global
economy. We looked at it as like this opportunity. So let's go where the likelihood... I still think
it's a contrarian move today, even though we've told people. Mexico is really hard. So we did
get lucky in some capacity. It's not become like a standard. Since then, I'd say Dubai has become
a standard. The Caymans have become a standard. Some US treasury loopholes have become a standard,
but people still aren't going to Mexico. So it's kind of interesting. Yeah, that was kind of our
outlook though is like where Warren Buffett's show me the incentives. So we really were like,
where are the incentives that raise the probability that we'll have success?
To cap off the story you were telling, you guys receive a no action letter
in Mexico. And what are the products that you guys then venture into that we would see today?
So now we have the ability to organize anything and we actually have API access to the stock
exchange in Mexico. We're like, okay, what could we do? We can do anything. We tried a few things,
but we really kind of had a second order like thought, what do we do that we think we can win?
And so we looked around in history and the world and just felt like there's not really the supply
for, I would say, the most popular, most boring investments in the world. We see a lot of need
in history for government debt on chain and we see a lot of demand for it. And we don't really see
that opportunity on the blockchain. And we don't also see entrepreneurs or people focused on it.
We see them focused on US treasuries, but we don't see them focused on other things. So
we decided to take a sliver of our opportunity and potential and we decided to become the company
that will provide the APIs and SDK or contract endpoint to tokenize the world sovereign debt on
chain, to tokenize the shortest term treasuries with the largest amount of liquidity from each
country and to make that available through interest bearing stable coins. And so that is our mission
statement. That's where we're focused. We did raise a series of small seed rounds. And so we said,
let's do five assets to prove who we are, make some traction and move forward. So the five assets
we tokenize for US treasuries, European treasuries, British treasuries, Brazilian treasuries,
and Mexican treasuries. And three of those five were the only company in the world who has the
ability to do those. Where early on did you see captive demand for those non-US treasuries on
chain? I think more we saw gaps in what happens in TradFi versus what's happening in the blockchain.
I think if I took that lens, where's the demand in the blockchain? It's a good question, but it
assumes that the right people are already on the blockchain. I think a lot of the demands right now
are highly speculative protocols, infrastructure. That's what I'm seeing. But I think 10 years from
now, it's going to be a totally different ecosystem. So really we thought what's missing
that historically has needed to be there before a nation grew in size. And it was bonds. If you look
back like what built Europe, it was bonds, the interface of the bond. It was less demand and
more of like cat in the hatting it. Where is it not? And then also like the need, we saw last
mile needs everywhere. Everyone wants to send money via remittance wallet, but then you see them and
they just wrap like USDC and then nothing. There's this missing last mile that we felt we could
fulfill. Since we've issued and promoted and pushed them out, we've partnered with people
to enable places that are not in Mexico and Brazil to issue stable coins in those currencies using
us as collateral. And we've seen demand there. We've seen that grow there. If you look at DeFi,
you look at our MXNE, which is what we call sovereign coin. So it's a stable coin denominated
in foreign currency, which uses our assets as collateral. We see quite a bit of activity
trading and using those for payments. Yeah. I like the framing there. We pick up efficiencies
on chain being faster settlement. Anyone can have an account, but the thought experiment of
where do we not see systems exist where we do in TradFi that create efficient systems.
And it just seems like an unsustainable reality that you have US dollars on chain and you're
going to have to go off chain to turn into any other sovereign currency when we live in a world
with how many sovereign currencies. I don't know the exact number, whether
147 countries. So something close to that number. We all talk about remittances, right? But remittances
doesn't work without an off ramp in the alternative country. I feel like the biggest
frustration with crypto or the blockchain today is the lack of understanding of where needs are
versus like, hey, how much TVL does this product have? That's what I'm going to focus on at the
moment. There's a lot of innovation that needs to happen still. We need to make space for that.
I guess that's kind of how I feel about it. In recent on-chain asset terms, we've had Bitcoin
for a long time. We've had Ethereum and Solana and then Longertail for a long time. We've seen
the rapid rise of stable coins now to some $230 billion market cap. Do you see the potential rise
of the MXN stable coin and other stable coins that you guys operate in as being commercially
driven and that people will want to own them for investment purposes? Or do you see it as more of a
workflow insert where the on-ramping and off-ramping from and to USD needs to become
more efficient? And because of that, it makes sense to have an MXN stable coin.
I think the first set of demand is going to come from the fact that we are going to make
on and off ramping from a local nation near free. Free or near free, depending on your use case.
Free for T plus one, for sure. I think that will drive so much demand and trust of being able to
on and off ramp that directly to a self-custody wallet that will see those volumes grow quite a
bit. I think people will start to recognize that since the yield for these underlying assets
are much higher than safer products, that our revenue opportunities are 10X those of normal
stable coins that you'll start to see people pay attention. I think that's the first order of
effect. The second is, it's ironic, but everything that's happening with tariffs
is really good for us. It's our idea. Because if you want to exchange your USDC or our Mexican
Sete's product, it is currently outperforming as a store of value, US-denominated products.
And so there's going to be chaos, in my opinion, for the next two years as we figure this out.
If you wanted to move safe assets on chain into a different product,
we're the only company that currently enables you to do that.
I think that there will be a lot of demand once people understand the potential. We built the
trust gap and they trust us. And just as an example, we magnify US products too. If you go to...
I'm trying to think, what's your blockchain of choice? I'll just pick Solana as an example.
If you go to Camino, you could short a US Treasury and do something with it,
or you could invest in one that's there. But it's possible to buy Sete's, short it,
and then with that buy a US Treasury. And now I have my US Treasury yields, but I also have
any underperformance of that emerging market. So I could boost yields up by 5% or 6% just by
shorting something else first. And this is a huge market in triad-fi, currency forwarding,
currency options. And DeFi is a better, more efficient place to do it. And so I think once
we are effective as a company, communicating and people trust us, they see we have the volumes,
we have the transparency and the security for those investments, it'll explode.
And retail, the individuals are completely excluded from that. I can go to cash,
but I can't go in my Chase account and say, okay, I want to be in pesos for the next six months.
It's impossible. You as a US person right now, if you wanted to buy just Mexican Treasuries,
you have to go through an ETF through JP Market Trace here, and they're returning 6% yields.
What are the fees on that?
3%. They're skimming about 3%. You go to us, you get full minus our take. So it's like 8% or 9%.
So it's way better. It's way more efficient to go through us. In addition to, if you wanted to hedge
a currency, say you wanted to buy pesos, but you want to hedge it with the dollar,
that's a complex TradFi product that's not really possible to do with like 300 bucks,
but it's totally possible to do on-chain.
And to your point about the inefficiency that we have, I think a lot of people, especially users
of crypto and even traditional financial venues in the US, don't have an appreciation of that globally.
I've tried to learn myself about the proliferation of Binance peer-to-peer
and these peer-to-peer on-ramps that you have, which is such a stark contrast to,
you have such efficient systems actually outside the US in what I would call traditional payments
with things like PIX in Brazil. Are those systems that you guys have integrated with
any capacity that you've utilized? And is there a reason that the product potentially functions
better outside the US in any capacity like that?
Yeah. I mean, you hit the nail on the head. For some reason, we have one of the worst payment
systems in the world, probably because we just have a lot of complexity, but in Mexico,
there's SPAY. It's real-time. So settlement in seconds, PIX. Our goal for each asset
is to enable on and off-ramping for free or near free, depending on the scenario.
So anytime there's a real-time payment system like PIX, we can do it for free.
If you just think about it, we own the asset in that country. We just have to sell it.
So if I can send funds to my brokerage immediately, I can also issue a token immediately.
If I can burn that and then issue a sell order immediately, I can sell it and send it to you
immediately. So Mexico is our first pilot for on and off-ramping. That'll officially be available
to the public next week. We are relatively certain that we'll be able to mint a token
on-chain denominated in peso for free and on-ramp it for free, at least two plus one.
And depending if we can get the yield of the volume to match the cost of a microloan,
it'll probably also be free to be instant. But worst case scenario, instant is five to seven
bits. So it's a huge improvement over what exists today. If you look at TradFi, it's like 7%.
If you look at like efficient TradFi, it's three. If you look at current state of
stables, it's like 1%, 100 bits. So this is like a 10X of the best thing out there.
So we're really excited by it and we hope it leads to trust in our asset
and that our assets proliferate because of that. So PIX is next. We're almost set up there.
Officially, we'll go to PIX in like July. I feel like we have an industry-wide innovators
dilemma in US fintech and finance because the system's so entrenched and you have people who
are profiting so immensely off of the credit card system, off of the way our bank accounts function
that my view at least is, especially in the context of stable coins, it's going to be
a reverse adoption for us, which is you get it in these other countries with smaller economies
and then eventually we'll be the late adopters. I think so. I also think that the reason the US
has done so well is historically it's proven to be a good place to start a company and a big economy
and I think it still is. I think you've got to be a little crazy to do what we're doing,
go to a country and be like, how's it work here? Where's the bank? It did take a little insanity.
I'm happy we were crazy enough to do it. We've gotten all the roadblocks out of the way now for
us to just scale efficiently given the right tools and resources. I think it took a little
bit of insanity for us to do it. I talked to a prominent startup investor. I said what I was
going to do is like, don't do that. That's a crazy idea. That's how you know you have to go and do
it, right? A little bit of stubbornness. I was like, whatever, man. For clarification, you guys
are a US company? We're multinational. We have EtherFuse Inc. It's our cap table essentially
and then our subsidiaries are in these local countries. The main one, EtherFuse MX.
Our regulatory umbrella is through EtherFuse MX. Our operations and the issuance of our assets
are all out of Mexico and then due to some investor feedback, we did set up some operations in
Switzerland. We issue out of Mexico and then we tokenize under Swiss regulation. I imagine
without touching on the secret sauce too much, the entity set up and the structuring here is
a big part of the undertaking I would imagine. Compare Brazil and Mexico. Brazil is pretty
sophisticated. It's kind of straightforward how to set up a company. Mexico is super complicated.
It's super slow and super costly. So yeah, just setting up an entity that's legal that you can
pay taxes on. Paying taxes on crypto is pretty insane in a country that has no kind of guidance.
So just getting to where we've gotten, stuff nobody sees is like a miracle to be honest.
The fact that we got a regulatory classification, then we needed a tax classification,
which was different. So all that stuff was a crazy amount of work and stress and that is done,
which is nice, but it was a huge undertaking. Yeah. Now the fun part.
Yeah. Grow. With stable coins today, you can hold dollars and send dollars all across the world.
That's amazing. Call out a phase one. You guys have built the system you were just talking about.
Call out a phase two where hopefully you can hold and send US dollars. You can also hold and send
other assets, other treasuries and trade them against each other very easily without this
reliance on an institutional account structure, without market hour constraints, all these legacy
systems or legacy limitations. Is this crypto's killer use case in your view? Is that what we've
been building for maybe at risk of upsetting the Bitcoin folks?
I think so. I mean, the Bitcoin folks, they have their use case, which is an awesome product that
stores value and it's independent from an economy. But I think crypto has a few other awesome use
cases. But I think one is just connecting the world efficiently through DeFi. There's this awesome
book called Mystery of Capital, which you should read. You may have read. Just creating a universal
process for trading across the world is an insane feat. What I view as crypto's biggest use case is
what the world's biggest market is today, which is the borax market. If I can remove an efficiency,
probably the most efficient channel in the world of sending money is the US to Mexico.
Our product has increased the yield that you could get by 3% and removed the cost of on and off
ramping to near zero. That's the most efficient channel. Now when I start to hit Nigeria and
Bangladesh, it's going to be way more efficient in the future. I think the biggest opportunity
is bringing the security of DeFi or bringing Forex onto DeFi and enabling the trust and
security of DeFi to facilitate exchange across the globe. The blockchain world has done really well
building the function f of x, but no one's really done well building x, which is the input.
We're focused on the things people will trade in the x. We've looked at the world and we've said
that stable bond refill solves three problems, store value and investment and payments.
If we look at those characteristics across the nations, what are the top 15? Our goal for the
next two years is to onboard those top 15 countries that have the highest store value,
the highest yields and are most used for remittances. We think if we can get those
15 assets on chain, we've brought 90% of the Forex market on chain and we've made it more
efficient, better investment, quicker, more reliable. I think that is crypto's killer use case.
The second is on and off ramping nations. To me, connecting a nation to crypto where the blockchain
is like connecting a nation to the internet or connecting a nation to electricity. In many cases,
we want to be the first person in these remote areas to provide an interest bearing asset,
denominating that currency that can on and off ramp for near free. Then we felt we've
on ramped that country. Those are the two scenarios that we really think about.
In those cases, as you guys see continued adoption, do you think people will look at
these stable coins and stable bonds each day? Will it be I pull up my phone and my app and I
see my balance and I know they're stable coins or will this be hidden behind some,
whether it's an agentic system, whether it's a messaging interface, a super app, something like
that? I think in a perfect world for us, people don't even really know they're using EtherFuse.
They look at a wallet, like I'm trying to think of somebody you guys know like Eldorado,
and they think Eldorado has an MXN account. It's not EtherFuse Sate or EtherFuse MXNE,
it's just abstracted. I think that's the killer use case. I think that's when people,
nobody cares. The real world doesn't care what it is or if it was AWS or Azure or GCP,
they just want the app to work. So for us, we're trying to not be the last thing you see,
we're trying to be like the AWS for sovereign debt. So I think in the future,
people won't really know it runs on the blockchain or what it is. It's just a wallet.
It's amazing. I've found that the people I know who actually know where stablecoins are being used,
especially the ones who use crypto, are the ones I know who are from the most
vulnerable or difficult markets from a geopolitical and economic perspective.
I have family in Iran because my dad grew up in Iran and I was talking about crypto with my family
and my Iranian grand uncle knew exactly about stablecoins and how they move and all that
because there's just such a distrust of how money works. Whereas PYUSD and even people I know who
might be in the Western hemisphere and hold dollars through a crypto account, they have no
idea it's sitting in stablecoins. It is interesting. I think part of that
leads to how we got here too. If you grew up or you're familiar with an area where the currency
fluctuates, you're yearning for a safe, stable asset. In your opinion, that's the dollar.
If you go to Argentina like you're saying or Iran, they know what it is. They can finally get access
through stablecoins. Sometimes I wonder, why are we the only people focusing on non-US assets?
I think it's because we brought the alternative perspective too. Just to play off that, I think
it's interesting. We have access to US dollars here in the US, but I don't have access to
emerging market investments quite efficiently as I think I should.
It's interesting how where you grew up in the context of your life leads to how you view
opportunity too. It's such a world-centric view,
especially in the context of history. I was having a conversation the other day where we were talking
about how no one knew the Roman Empire fell until hundreds of years later. To take a view that you
only ever want to own US dollars is to say that you think the US will be the only dominant currency
for the foreseeable future of history ever. Which maybe, maybe not.
Hopefully, yeah. Hopefully for us. I win-win no matter what, but I don't think so.
Especially if you look at what Europe is doing with Mica, it was fundamentally built to protect
their sovereignty and their currency. If you look, they have restrictions on
non-European limits and things like that, that they don't have if your currency is Mica compliance
and denominated in the euro. I think we're going to see this start to happen more and more across
the world where you have these regulatory bodies say almost like these new tariffs.
I look at Mica as a tariff, to be honest. It's like some added complexity to promote
an internal economy. I think we'll start to see those with stablecoins
probably in the next five years or so. Hopefully, we're well established and we can meet those
demands. But yeah, I think we're going to see the world change quite a bit in the next five years.
You guys are in a very interesting position because you are going to be offering these
assets to what is a really wide demographic of people when you think about the different
profiles in these countries. From my perspective, it seems like it's a bit of a jump ball in terms
of the offerings of these assets and controlling the end user in the sense that it could be JP
Morgan. It could be Apple, your former employer. It could be a government. It could even be NATO
or some kind of multinational organization. Maybe that's a bit of a stretch, but
I think you understand the sentiment. Do you think they will all try and get into this game?
In my view, it's only logical that they would. But I'm curious who you think moves here and then who
is the issuer who's controlling the end user in the future?
Ironically, I think the only thing that has enabled the legacy financial system to not
completely dominate the blockchain ecosystem is fear and regulation because they have a lot to
lose. So regulation saved us. Regulation has saved us. This gray area has enabled the opportunity
for us to have upward mobility. I mean, just think about it. Tether is what, $130 billion?
Yeah. No, what's that line? Regulation favors the incumbent, right?
Yeah. JP Morgan Chase is $4 trillion. JP Morgan Chase doesn't need Tether and they don't need
Circle at all. The second they know how they can operate and it's clear,
they're all issuing stable coins and no one's going to care. I have Chase. If my account is
underlying stable coins, the JP Morgan coin, I won't care. I don't think about it. I trust them
enough. I think it's going to be interesting to see what happens in the US. I do believe
that the established players like Tether and Circle will survive and they'll have a place.
But I think these new ones who are, and I hate to say this because I like a lot of these people,
I hope I'm wrong, but I think it'll be a less trusted resource once regulation is clear.
Unless you get in the billions of volume or you have some niche,
pretty sure that the banks are going to come for us all. Now, our benefit is these emerging markets
are way behind in a lot of stuff. When we issue an asset, we're the first company that comes in to
do it. I think we have 10 to 15 years to make an impact before those regulatory bodies really
do enough work to let their banking systems issue stable coins. So that's our philosophy.
10 to 15 years isn't bad.
Yeah, not too bad. We can do a lot with that. But especially just looking at Mexico,
it's so old. How it works is so bureaucratic compared to the US, which is also slow.
I think before banks, and we're talking to a lot of them by the way, so we understand their
dilemma. Before Mexican banks felt comfortable enough to issue large volumes, a lot has to
happen. And I think the US has to move first. It was really strange how we heard no's.
So some of our assets are in Europe. And the early stages, the problem was finding a custodian who
would say yes to us, and we got turned down by a lot of people.
Interesting. So that was like an operation choke point 2.0 issue in Europe, just like we have here.
It's crazy. These are big banks too. I don't want to name names, but the second Trump won,
I had three of them email me back saying, hey, we're looking to be more competitive.
And I was like, dude, it was really hard to find our initial custodians. And all our custodians
are large and well-trusted. And so that was part of the problem. But I think the US leads
and the rest of the world follows their guidance.
If you take those banks or any others as an example, were they building crypto product and
were they trying to get ready when Trump wasn't president and we were in a hostile regime,
or do you think they're a little flat-footed?
I think they're flat-footed. I think the only emerging, it's not an emerging market,
but the only bank that I'd say global that addresses emerging market needs that's really
trying, was trying back then was BBVA. They have a platform in Switzerland.
They've been working on some things. So they were kind of trying, but the sense of urgency
that they should have had was definitely not there. This is a huge disruptor, especially for
emerging markets. 50% of BBVA's revenue comes just from Mexico as an example.
So in my opinion, I would be doing everything I can if I was the CEO of BBVA to ensure that
I'm leading this space in Mexico. We work with them. They work with us. They're friendly to us.
So maybe we can help them get there. I think that they are now flat-footed and trying to recover
quite a bit. In the US, we've made major strides. People get very down on some of these topics, but
the Bitcoin ETF, exchange trading on traditional brokerages in terms of just giving normal people
access to crypto. My sense is that that's happened a lot less elsewhere. And it's funny,
in our local circumstance, I think that that is probably actually stymied DeFi adoption to a sense.
My view is people used to go to DeFi because traditional trading opportunities were limited.
And now Coinbase is listing more assets. You can go and buy the Bitcoin ETF on various brokerages.
Do you think more globally that that lack of crypto trading experience with traditional
banks, asset managers pushes people to DeFi? Is that a growth catalyst for DeFi?
Yeah. When regulation is unclear, it's the only launch pad. There is Seify, but is there a
centralized... I don't know the best way to say Seify, but... Seify works.
Okay. Seify. Seify, in my experience, has felt a lot like extortion where it's like,
hey, we're the only way for you to bridge to the blockchain. So give us a bunch of money and we'll
let your token. But DeFi has been a way that we could use skills to grow without any gatekeepers.
So my opinion over the next 10 years, centralized exchanges influence will be reduced,
especially as things become more clear in ways that a wallet could directly bridge you to the
blockchain, not necessarily a big company. And I think DeFi's influence will increase
for a few reasons. Even though regulation clearing up will make it easier for you to get access,
there's still going to be this nuance. So if you take like equities as an example,
we deliberately chose not to engage in equities because once you start selling in equity,
there's a hundred X more issues you have to worry about.
In my opinion, all these new equity platforms coming out, they'll have these restrictions,
which will make it harder for you to trade off-ramping, on-ramping and things like that.
So I think DeFi will still have a place where someone who has a regulatory body that is
favorable to them that can issue on DeFi will have an asset that is more freely transferable.
Both things are going to happen. There'll be better traditional access using blockchain
technology available to people in highly regulated areas. But also there will be certain things
that can only be done at DeFi like non-restricted tokens that can be freely transferable that
someone in Venezuela could buy on DeFi or that'll have to happen on DeFi and there
will always be a market for that. And I want to pick your brain on
your views for the future a little bit. And first in that vein, you mentioned wallets
for an ether fuse, for example, is better wallets one of the best things that can happen for your
guys' business looking at how you're acquiring users? Best case scenario is you're a big wallet.
You get my SDK and you mint and burn directly. Better wallets is our favorite partners, right?
There's nothing in between the user and us except for this interface and there's a lot for the
wallet to gain and there's a lot for the user to have. So like hypothetically-
So if you're a wallet listening-
Yeah, if you're a wallet, come talk to me. I can enable you multi-currency accounts
that are yield bearing that earn you different revenue while you just fundamentally give
your users like a wise experience. Wise is bank accounts and different currencies,
they don't earn yield and they let you send money. I can do that same thing for you just
by giving you my SDK if you're a self custody wallet.
It's the best business in the book, isn't it? You just hold assets for someone and earn money
for doing it for something that you don't even control or issue.
Yeah. And even if you're a self custody wallet, you're not technically even holding them.
It's just you work through our affiliate program and you earn a portion of the yield
that that customer generates. So you don't even need like an MTL license.
That's exactly like Coinbase's circle agreement, right? There's no difference there really.
Yeah, exactly. And Coinbase wallet does this. Coinbase, I don't know what your thoughts are.
I think they're going to do really well. The way they're vertically integrated,
they already show preference over currencies. And so if you bought MXNE, it would be like a
preferred asset. They really get it and they're able to do it because they have the whole stack.
I've heard they're going to become a bank here, which is a killer use case too. So it seems like
they get it. They're making a push into non-USD stablecoins, as I'm sure you've seen.
Yeah, we're a big part of it. If you see their dashboards, MXNE is on it.
Well, in that vein, and to close out a bit here, where do you see either fuse or where do you hope
either fuse is in coming months and years? And what's the worldview that pushes you guys forward
in the right direction? Our aim for the next two years is to onboard 90%
of all assets used for remittances the last mile, and that we can on and off ramp onto those assets.
You can mint and burn essentially from the local banking system. So that's the next two years.
The next five years, every country, we have an interest bearing asset denominated in that
currency that can on and off ramp. And we facilitate local stablecoins to nominate those
currencies. So that's the goal for us is to on-ramp those countries and bring Forex on-chain.
And we want to be laser-focused on building the most robust assets with transparency,
with third-party checks and validation and verifications, improving our liquidity for
each asset and the utility of on and off ramping those assets. So next five years,
we hope to bring Forex on-chain through our assets on any platform, on any blockchain,
and that that is a trusted resource, that he diffuses a trusted brand just like Circle is
or Tether is. Awesome. Well, we'll leave it there with the hopes of a more globally, economically
interconnected world. Dave, thanks for joining us and hopefully you'll come back soon.
All right. Thanks, Wyatt. Appreciate it. Thanks for listening to another episode of On the Brink
with Castle Island. To find out more about Castle Island, visit castleisland.vc. To listen to all
of our podcast episodes, please go to onthebrink-podcast.com or just click on the
tab on our website. Thanks for listening.